<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Timur Borkhodoev</title>
    <link>https://terracotapie.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Timur Borkhodoev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017 Timur Borkhodoev</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 22:31:45 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://terracotapie.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim</title>
      <link>https://terracotapie.github.io/projects/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 22:31:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terracotapie.github.io/projects/vim/</guid>
      <description>Back to coding in C/C++ this year for an Advanced Operating System course. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using vim the last year for the intro. Implementing a few utilities for EXT2 file system required reading through a number of structs and jump around quite a bit. Took me 5-6 hours to succumb and use IDE, namely Clion.
Multiple problem were encountered with basic vim setup:
 lack of auto-completion go-to-definition Poor organization and way too many plugins  All of that could be solved with YouCompleteMe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toy Compiler</title>
      <link>https://terracotapie.github.io/projects/toycompiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 18:34:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terracotapie.github.io/projects/toycompiler/</guid>
      <description>For a while I wanted to create a toy compiler. Just so I can boast about which language is the best 🔥.So I took a grad level course. Few things to learn here:
 Code generation
Your code -&amp;gt; intermidiate representation -&amp;gt; assembly -&amp;gt; machine code
 Grammars and language design
i.e. what makes a good/bad language? Does one needs to have pointer arithmetics? Should language be expressive/permissive or maybe developers should focus and making it statically analyzable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating blog using hugo</title>
      <link>https://terracotapie.github.io/projects/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 15:00:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terracotapie.github.io/projects/blog/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to create a personal blog for a long time. I did some research and decided to go with hugo. There&amp;rsquo;s one main reason for using hugo over anything else:
 amazing speed org-mode support out-of-the box 😃 emojis?  As a matter of fact this post is written fully in org. I started with the quickstart guide. There&amp;rsquo;s a really great minimalistic theme cocoa-eh. After messing with a config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kernel module monitoring syscalls</title>
      <link>https://terracotapie.github.io/projects/kernel-intercept/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 19:13:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://terracotapie.github.io/projects/kernel-intercept/</guid>
      <description>So in one the OS classes we had to write a kernel module that intercepts system calls of choice. For that matter we were introduced to the concept of system call table. There is a good description here. We start with a snippet taken from tldp.
#include &amp;lt;linux/kernel.h&amp;gt;	/* Needed for KERN_INFO */ #include &amp;lt;linux/init.h&amp;gt;	/* Needed for the macros */ extern void* sys_call_table[]; /* Apparently kernel doesn&#39;t export the address starting 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>